Pray for Michael Sullivan.
Road to Perdition is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Sam Mendes.
Mike Sullivan works as a hit man for crime boss John Rooney.
Sullivan views Rooney as a father figure, however after his son is witness to a killing, Mike Sullivan finds himself on the
run in attempt to save the life of his son and at the same time looking for revenge on those who wronged him.
Michael Sullivan, played by Tom Hanks.
John Rooney, played by Paul Newman.
Harlen Maguire, played by Jude Law.
Michael Sullivan, Jr., played by Tyler Hoechlin.
Connor Rooney, played by Daniel Craig.
Frank Nitti, played by Stanley Tucci.
Road to Perdition is a 2002 American crime tragedy film directed by Sam Mendes and written by David Self, based on the first
volume of the DC Comics graphic novel series of the same name by Max Allan Collins and Richard Piers Rayner.
It stars Tom Hanks, Tyler Hoechlin, Paul Newman (in his final live-action theatrical film
role), Jude Law, Jennifer Jason Leigh, Stanley Tucci and Daniel Craig.
Set in 1931, during the Great Depression, the film follows a mob enforcer and his son as
they seek vengeance against the mobster who murdered the rest of their family.
The film explores themes such as father-son
relationships and the consequences of violence.
Road to Perdition was screened at the 59th Venice International Film Festival
on August 31, 2002, where it was nominated for the Golden Lion.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on July 12, 2002, and was a box
office success, grossing $183.4 million against its $80 million budget.
Critics received it well and praised Mendes's direction, Conrad L.
Hall's cinematography, and the cast's performances.
At the 75th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Supporting Actor for Newman, Best
Original Score, Best Sound Editing, Best Sound Mixing, and Best Art Direction.
Hall was posthumously awarded the Oscar for Best Cinematography.
The film explores themes of hotel, farm, hitman, illinois, great depression.
The tone is emotional and intense.